Guide to the Robert J. Havighurst Papers 1921-1991
University of Chicago Library
- Series V: Society and Education
  - Educational Resources Info Ctr. Clearinghouse on Urban Ed., 1980 (Box 69, Folder 12)
  - Catholic Education, 1967 (Box 69, Folder 13)
  - Education and Ethnicity, 1945-1955 (Box 69, Folder 14)
  - Manuscripts, 1976 (Box 69, Folder 15)
  - Magnet Schools, 1976-1977 (Box 69, Folder 16)
  - Ethnic Studies in Chicago, 1975-1977 (Box 69, Folder 17)
  - "The Preparation of Schools for Intergroup Relations," n.d. (Box 69, Folder 18)
  - Review of Whitetown, USA, 1970 (Box 69, Folder 19)
  - Greeks in Chicago, 1977 (Box 69, Folder 20)
  - Education and Ethnicity, 1977 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Integration in Ed, 1964 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Beecher, John, 1963 (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Interracial Neighborhoods, 1978-1979 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Pates, Harold. "Condescension: A Study of Attitudes of Teachers Who Work with Children in All-Black Schools," 1976 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Race Relations, 1969-1971 (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - Schreiber, Emanuel. "Beyond the Chrysanthemum and the Sword: Identity Problems of Urban-Educated Japanese Youth," May 1971 (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Docs, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - Separation in Education, 1971 (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - Cultural Pluralism, 1976-77 (Box 70, Folder 10)
  - Cultural Pluralism, 1976 (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - Cultural Pluralism, 1971-1974 (Box 70, Folder 12)
  - Davis Symposium, 1946-1955 (Box 70, Folder 13)
  - Color and Social Class in Metro America, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 14)
  - "Social Class Factors in Coping Style and Competence," August 1971 (Box 70, Folder 15)
  - Minority Subcultures, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 16)
  - "Education and Intergroup Relations," n.d. (Box 70, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Reviews and Correspondence, 1969-1972 (Box 70, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 79-78 (Box 70, Folder 19)
  - Cultural Pluralism, 1978-1981 (Box 70, Folder 20)
  - Cultural Pluralism, 74-77 (Box 70, Folder 21)
  - "Social Mobility, Education, and the Underclass," n.d. (Box 70, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 23)
  - Cuba and Puerto Rico, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 24)
  - Tables, Outlines, Bibl., 1971; "The Dilemma of Education of Mexican-Americans" (Box 70, Folder 25)
  - Other Minority Groups (Box 70, Folder 26)
  - Test Scores of Chinese Children, 1969 (Box 70, Folder 27)
  - "Summary of the Status of Elderly Asians in Chicago," 1976 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Social Class and Ethnicity, 72-75 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Langman, Lauren, 1974 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Social Mobility and Education, 1965-1977 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Social Mobility and Education, 1973-1976 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Social Mobility and Education, 66-74 (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous MS and Correspondence, Sociology, 72-76 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Tables, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Charts and Tables, n.d. (1-2) (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - "Individual and Group Rights in a Democracy," Jan-Feb 1976 (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - Intergroup Relations, 45-74 (Box 71, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, MS, Outlines, Correspondence, 74-76 (Box 71, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Materials, 68-71 (Box 71, Folder 13)
  - "The Crisis for Integration in American Education," 66-67 (Box 71, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Materials on Racial Integration, 66-68 (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Materials on Segregation, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - "The Bearing of Integration on Educational Problems," March, 1964 (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Columbia, SC, 1972 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Minority Attitudes, 1968 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Ethnic Groups and Education, 1955 (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Intergroup Education, 1955 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Integration, 67-68 (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - School Integration, 1974 (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - Integration Problems, 64-66 (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - Public School Integration, 1964 (Box 72, Folder 11)
  - Integration of Schools, 1965 (Box 72, Folder 12)
  - Integration of Schools, 1967 (Box 72, Folder 13)
  - Science Education, 49-50 (Box 72, Folder 14)
  - Hampshire College, 69-71 (Box 72, Folder 15)
  - Phi Delta Kappa Research Symposium on Leadership, 70-71 (Box 72, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Mats on Education and Adolescence (Box 72, Folder 17)
  - Committee on Urban Education, 65-67 (1 of 2) (Box 72, Folder 18)
  - Committee on Urban Education, 65-67 (2 of 2) (Box 72, Folder 19)
  - Committee for Urban Education, "Proposal for an Urban Education Laboratory" (Box 72, Folder 20)
  - Committee on Urban Education, 1960 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Comm. UE, "Institutional Collaboration to Improve Urban Public Education with Special Reference to the City of Chicago," Research Proposal, Oct 1966 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - CUE Research and Development Ctr in Urban Ed, Oct 15 1965 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Mats, 1978 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - The East Orange Educational Plan, 1964-1968 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - "Social Status Factors in Intelligence Test Items," Kenneth Eells, vol 1 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - "Social Status Factors in Intelligence Test Items," Kenneth Eells, vol 2 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 71-79 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Mats, 60-75 (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Mats, 75-78 (Box 73, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Mats, 70-79 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Shane, Harold G., 75-79 (1 of 2) (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Shane, Harold G., 75-79 (2 of 2) (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Future and Education, 71-72 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Grouping of Children, 47-59 (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Kaner, Charence J. "Presidential Address for the History of Educational Soc." 1978 (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Chicago Area Faculty for a Freeze on the Nuclear Arms Race, 1982 (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - Education for World Peace, 40-75 (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - 49-75 Miscellaneous Mats (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - Int’l Ed., 48-78 (Box 74, Folder 10)
  - Leisure Activity, 67-80 (Box 74, Folder 11)
  - Leisure Activity, Manuscripts, 57-75 (Box 74, Folder 12)
  - Leisure Activity, 57-78 (Box 74, Folder 13)
  - Leisure Activity, 59-72 (Box 74, Folder 14)
  - Leisure Activity, 71-83 (Box 74, Folder 15)
  - Leisure Activity of the Aged, 69-71 (Box 74, Folder 16)
  - Leisure Activity, 59-72 (Box 74, Folder 17)
  - Leisure Activity, notes, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 18)
  - Leisure Activity of the Aged, 59-72 (Box 74, Folder 19)
  - Lifestyle and Leisure Patterns, 72-79 (Box 74, Folder 20)
  - Mass Culture, 67 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Montessori Principles, 64 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Educational Psychologist, 69-72 (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Personality, 75-76 (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Mats (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - "Play and Sport in the Maturation of Youth," 1975 (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - ED 411, Mats, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 7)
  - Pygmalion Study, 68-73 (Box 75, Folder 8)
  - "Crisis in the Cities," June 67 (Box 75, Folder 9)
  - Education and Reading, 1967 (Box 75, Folder 10)
  - Personality Development, 42-62 (Box 75, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Mats, 59-74 (Box 75, Folder 12)
  - Stats Methods, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 13)
  - TV and Radio, 1976 (Box 75, Folder 14)
  - Nat’l Consultation on Technology and Human Values, 67 (Box 75, Folder 15)
  - Ed of Women, 60-63 (Box 75, Folder 16)
- Series VI: Morris Study
  - Blackburn, Robert T., 1975-1980 (Box 75, Folder 17)
  - Blackburn, Robert T., 1978-1980 (Box 75, Folder 18)
  - University of Chicago Periodicals, 65-67 (Box 75, Folder 19)
  - Motivation and Higher Education, 51-59 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Education and Values, 59-66 (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Alternative Schools, 78-81 (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Opposing the Critics, 72-77 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Education Reform, 62-77 (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Alternative Schools, 71-86 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Criticism of Education, 68-74 (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Neighborhood Schools, 67-72 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Analysis of Schools, 67-73 (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - Silberman, Charles E., 70-81 (Box 76, Folder 10)
  - Black Schools in Chicago, 62-71 (Box 76, Folder 11)
  - Black Colleges, 62-74 (Box 76, Folder 12)
  - Society and Education, 61-74 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Instruments Used in Morris Study, 1943-46 (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Social Class Questionnaire and Chicago Interest, 1942-1945 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Interest Index, 1939 (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Student Beliefs, 43-46 (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Problem Checklist and Life Problems Questionnaire, 42-43 (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Personality Tests, 1943 (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - Reading Questionnaire, 1945 (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - Family Relations Questionnaire, 45-48 (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - Strength of Conscience Questionnaire, 1946 (Box 77, Folder 10)
  - "Guess Who" Questionnaire, 43-49 (Box 77, Folder 11)
  - "Guess Who" Questionnaire, 43-46 (Box 77, Folder 12)
  - "Guess Who" Adult Questionnaire, 43-49 (Box 77, Folder 13)
  - Essay Questions, 43-46 (Box 77, Folder 14)
  - Checklist of Personal Characteristics, 42-45 (Box 77, Folder 15)
  - Portrait Matching and Character Sketching, 43-82 (Box 77, Folder 16)
  - Behavior Rating Scale and Family Relations Rating, 46 (Box 77, Folder 17)
  - Personality Diagnosis and Stories from Pictures, 43-45 (Box 77, Folder 18)
  - Intelligence, Ability, and Aptitude Tests, 1937-1943 (Box 77, Folder 19)
  - Achievement Tests, 27-48 (Box 77, Folder 20)
  - Behavioral Data, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 21)
  - Physical Data, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 22)
  - Morris-History Project (Box 77, Folder 23)
  - Field Workers in Morris (Box 77, Folder 24)
  - Morris Project-Report from Field Workers (Box 77, Folder 25)
  - Morris Project-Publication Agreements (Box 77, Folder 26)
  - Vogt, E.Z. (Box 77, Folder 27)
  - Morris Study-1947-R.J. Havighurst, (R. Stone, Interviewer) (Box 77, Folder 28)
  - History of Morris Study (Box 77, Folder 29)
  - Beekman (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Report on Small Town Study, by Margaret Mead (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Morris Fellowship (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Morris Follow-Up Study (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Motivation-Morris Data (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Roster (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Character Studies (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Parent Attitudes and Goals (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - Character Study-Guess Who-Young Adults (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - Factor Analysis (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - School and Character Education (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - Moral Character (Box 78, Folder 12)
  - Education 324-Character Education-Lectures (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - "The US-Centered Approach to Character Education", "Character Education" (Box 78, Folder 14)
  - Clinical Case Conference, 1947-48 (Box 78, Folder 15)
  - Summary of Clinical Conference Meetings (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Character Study-Committee Meeting Minutes (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Variables (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Character Study-1949 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Rel. Ed. Motel (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Clinical Case Conference-1949-1950 (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - Grant Foundation (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Rel Ed (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - Outline-Method and Results of the Direct Factor Analysis (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - Character Study-1948-1949 (Box 79, Folder 10)
  - Master Check List (Morris) (Box 79, Folder 11)
  - Character Study-Instruments (Box 79, Folder 12)
  - Character Study-The Person I Would Like to Be Like (Box 79, Folder 13)
  - List of Names (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - PMA Study (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Morris Project-Mrs. Neugarten (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Morris Project-History (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Morris Study-Charts (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Morris Project-Forms and Questionnaires (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Report on Conf. Between U of C Represent. And Community Leaders of Morris, 1949 (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Memoranda on Research Projects (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - Reactions to Publications in Morris-1949 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Morris Study (Box 80, Folder 10)
  - Hammer, Kenneth (Box 80, Folder 11)
  - Notes (Box 80, Folder 12)
  - Morris Project-Interviews (Box 80, Folder 13)
  - Morris Project-Marchia Meeker (Box 80, Folder 14)
  - Personality Tests (Box 80, Folder 15)
  - Morris Project-Dorothy Neubauer (Box 80, Folder 16)
  - Morris Project-Finances (Box 80, Folder 17)
  - "Patterns of Social Mobility: A Report Based Upon the Prairie City Study," by Dorothy T. Brown and Tom Moorefield (2 copies) (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Prairie City School Appraisal (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - Prairie City School Appraisal, Part III (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Bibliography-Midwest-Jonesville-Prairie City Study (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Follow Up of Prairie City Study (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Morris Study-Doll (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - T-66 Jay Lyons M.C. Study (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Hutchings, John (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Carver, Betty Broderick (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - Classen, Harrietta Jones (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - Bunton, Joy (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - Carter, Nancy Maunder (Box 82, Folder 9)
  - Carroll, Robert (Box 82, Folder 10)
  - Broderick, Mary Jane F. (Box 82, Folder 11)
  - Belt, Arlene Ammons (Box 82, Folder 12)
  - Slater, John (Box 82, Folder 13)
  - Button, Mrs. Charles (Box 82, Folder 14)
  - Cameron, Jean (Box 82, Folder 15)
  - Fisher, Robert (Box 82, Folder 16)
  - Edmonson, Norman (Box 82, Folder 17)
  - Di John, Richard (Box 82, Folder 18)
  - Finn, Charlotte Eich (Box 82, Folder 19)
  - Francis, Jay (Box 82, Folder 20)
  - Garling, Margaret Bansback (Box 82, Folder 21)
  - Hougas, James (Box 82, Folder 22)
  - Johnson, Charles (Box 82, Folder 23)
  - Hansen, Frank (Box 82, Folder 24)
  - Panish, Rosemary (Box 82, Folder 25)
  - Kay, Allen (Box 82, Folder 26)
  - Konjevich, Joan Lyons (Box 82, Folder 27)
  - Lewis, Ruth (Box 82, Folder 28)
  - Lyons, Jay (Box 82, Folder 29)
  - Marquez, Doris Kress (Box 82, Folder 30)
  - Peterson, William (Box 82, Folder 31)
  - McTaugue, Gerald (Box 82, Folder 32)
  - Woodruff, Janet (Box 82, Folder 33)
  - Roseland, David (Box 82, Folder 34)
  - Sabino, Mary Jane Nelson (Box 82, Folder 35)
  - Sterritt, Patsy Ann Button (Box 82, Folder 36)
  - White, Janet Southcombe (Box 82, Folder 37)
  - Prairie City Follow Up (Box 82, Folder 38)
- Series VII: Quincy Youth Development Commission
  - QYDC (Box 82, Folder 39)
  - Roles with Schools (Box 82, Folder 40)
  - QYDC: Role with Welfare Council (Box 82, Folder 41)
  - QYDC: Role with Courts (Box 82, Folder 42)
  - QYDC: Role with Churches (Box 82, Folder 43)
  - QYDC: Role with Others (Box 82, Folder 44)
  - 4.63 Role with Agencies (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - QYDC Role with YM (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - QYDC Role with YW (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - QYDC Role with Boy Scouts (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - 4.635 Role with Family Service Agency (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Overview-RJ Hanbum (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - Paul Bowman (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - Reports of Meetings, Seminars, etc (Box 83, Folder 8)
  - 4.11 Introduction of Project-RJH Interviews, 1-73 (Box 83, Folder 9)
  - QYDC Staff Minutes, Staff Meetings (Box 83, Folder 10)
  - Reprints-Quincy Youth Development Center (Box 83, Folder 11)
  - 5.41 Plans and Progress Reports (Box 83, Folder 12)
  - 1.34 Staff Contacts in Other Communities (Box 83, Folder 13)
  - 4.634 Consultant Role-Girl Scouts (Box 83, Folder 14)
  - Screening Program (Box 83, Folder 15)
  - Reports of Meetings, Seminars, etc. (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - Overachievers Interviews (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Conferences with Principals (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Reports of Meetings, etc. (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Program Plans-intellectually gifted (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - Work with Gifted Children, QYDC (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - Progress Reports and Plans (Box 84, Folder 7)
  - Science Club (Box 84, Folder 8)
  - Dramatic Programs (Box 84, Folder 9)
  - 5.344 (Box 84, Folder 10)
  - Creative Writing Programs (Box 84, Folder 11)
  - YMCA Fine Arts Program (Box 84, Folder 12)
  - Committee-Chaddock’s Boys School (Box 84, Folder 13)
  - Executive Committee (Box 84, Folder 14)
  - Commission Minutes of Meetings (Box 84, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Business (Box 84, Folder 16)
  - Publications Committee Meeting (Box 84, Folder 17)
  - Professional Committee Minutes (Box 84, Folder 18)
  - Miss B. Day Report (Box 84, Folder 19)
  - Quincy Confidential (Box 84, Folder 20)
  - Center for Community Youth Development (Box 84, Folder 21)
  - Moorman Negotiations (Box 84, Folder 22)
  - Monthly Reports from Quincy (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Quincy ‘Consultants’ Report’, December 1, 1951 (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Evaluation of Conselors (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - 4.11 Introduction of Project-Bertha Day Memorandum and Correspondence (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - 4.11 Introduction of Project-Bertha Day Interviews #1-80 (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - QYDC Staff Contacts (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - QYDC Staff Policies (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - QYDC Procedures: Screening and the Schools (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - 2.23-Lists of Selected Children (Box 85, Folder 9)
  - QYDC Procedures: Screening, general memos (Box 85, Folder 10)
  - General Info (Box 85, Folder 11)
  - Talent Projects (Box 85, Folder 12)
  - Quincy Rural Youth Project (Box 85, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous re: Study of Students (Box 85, Folder 14)
  - U.S. Office of Education Research (Box 85, Folder 15)
  - 6.2 Research re: Children (Box 85, Folder 16)
  - QYDC Procedures, Instruments, General Information (Box 85, Folder 17)
  - Adjective Check List (Box 85, Folder 18)
  - Quincy Test Instruments (Box 85, Folder 19)
  - QYDC Sociometric Testing (Box 85, Folder 20)
  - BDC (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Roster of Talented Children in Quincy (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Talent Studies (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Quincy-Gifted Child (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Play Therapy (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Slow Learner Interview: Jr. High (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Slow Learner Interview: Franklin (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Quincy Interviews, 1957 (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - QYDC Sociological Baseline Data (Box 86, Folder 9)
  - Teachers Workshop 1954: Lower Grade Discussion Group (Box 86, Folder 10)
  - 5.453 (Box 86, Folder 11)
  - Slow Learner Project (Box 86, Folder 12)
  - 5.452 Slow Learner Project (Franklin) (Box 86, Folder 13)
  - 5.52 (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - Teachers Workshop 1954 1. Summary Report (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - Slow Learner Research (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Delinquency Study (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Y-Group Interviews (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - Dropout Interviews (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - Liddle and Sachdat (Box 87, Folder 7)
  - 3.34 Dropout Interviews (Box 87, Folder 8)
  - Mobility Study (Box 87, Folder 9)
  - Mobility Material (Box 87, Folder 10)
  - Mobility Study (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - MDB Mobility (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - Summer 1963 Current Information (Four changes in SC Ratings) (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Mobility Study Girls (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - Chapter XI: Early Adult Social Status and Social Mobility (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - Chapter XII: Adult Competence (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - Early Marriage (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - Paul’s Interview (Summer 1963) (Box 88, Folder 8)
  - Gene Blanchett 5-54 (Box 88, Folder 9)
  - Harry Bryant 2-54 (Box 88, Folder 10)
  - Mary Busbey (Box 88, Folder 11)
  - Patsy Cobb (Box 88, Folder 12)
  - Donna Davis (Box 88, Folder 13)
  - Marion French (Box 88, Folder 14)
  - Roger Gamble (Box 88, Folder 15)
  - Jill Ganka (Box 88, Folder 16)
  - Peggy Garner (Box 88, Folder 17)
  - Russell Gilker (Box 88, Folder 18)
  - Connie Gille (Box 88, Folder 19)
  - Edith Goodwin (Box 88, Folder 20)
  - Dennis Gorman (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Bonnie Hendrian (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Robert Harness (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Patsy Henze (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - Nancy Hodel (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Melvin Hollyman (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Patricia Hopkins (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - Ellen Hutter (Box 89, Folder 8)
  - Doris Hysell (Box 89, Folder 9)
  - Ronald Jackson (Box 89, Folder 10)
  - Sandra Jackson (Box 89, Folder 11)
  - Robert Kelley (Box 89, Folder 12)
  - Kroger, Leroy (Box 89, Folder 13)
  - Lane, Barbara (Box 89, Folder 14)
  - Sharon Leake (Box 89, Folder 15)
  - Brian MacKinnon (Box 89, Folder 16)
  - Wuanetta Likes (Box 89, Folder 17)
  - Mike Mallory (Box 89, Folder 18)
  - Alfred Mason (Box 89, Folder 19)
  - Dale Mason (Box 89, Folder 20)
  - Donnetta Mason (Box 89, Folder 21)
  - Mirie Maynor (Box 89, Folder 22)
  - McCarthy, Arlys (Box 89, Folder 23)
  - Jerilyn McKenny (Box 89, Folder 24)
  - Charlotte Meyer (Box 89, Folder 25)
  - Meyer, Sharon (Box 89, Folder 26)
  - Leandra Miles (Box 89, Folder 27)
  - Milhauser, James (Box 89, Folder 28)
  - Everett Miller (Box 89, Folder 29)
  - Richard Morrison (Box 89, Folder 30)
  - Parent Interview: Mother of Wanda Moore and Judy Moore (Box 89, Folder 31)
  - Dennis Morrall (Box 89, Folder 32)
  - Naderhoff, Sharon (Box 89, Folder 33)
  - Wanda Otto (Box 89, Folder 34)
  - Owen, Karen (Box 89, Folder 35)
  - Helena Pearl (Box 89, Folder 36)
  - Phil Pippinger (Box 89, Folder 37)
  - David Pritchett (Box 89, Folder 38)
  - Dan Reeves (Box 89, Folder 39)
  - Billy Reichert (Box 89, Folder 40)
  - James Reid (Box 89, Folder 41)
  - Sonja Reynolds (Box 89, Folder 42)
  - Jacqueline Rickman (Box 89, Folder 43)
  - Reinberg, David (Box 89, Folder 44)
  - Barbara Riley (Box 89, Folder 45)
  - Paul Robbins (Box 89, Folder 46)
  - Karen Rosenkoetter (Box 89, Folder 47)
  - Joyce Rost (Box 89, Folder 48)
  - DeWayneRuble (Box 89, Folder 49)
  - Rueter, Penny (Box 89, Folder 50)
  - Sapp, Clara (Box 89, Folder 51)
  - Norma Sass (Box 89, Folder 52)
  - Alan B. Saylor (Box 89, Folder 53)
  - Barbara Schaffer (Box 89, Folder 54)
  - Peter Schelp (Box 89, Folder 55)
  - Schmutzler, Paul (Box 89, Folder 56)
  - Schnack, Kay (Box 89, Folder 57)
  - Scott, Connie (Box 89, Folder 58)
  - Scott, Stephans (Box 89, Folder 59)
  - Dorothy Seckman (Box 89, Folder 60)
  - Simmons, Mike (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Sloan, Sandra (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Richard Smiley (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Lenora Smith (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Richard Torbeck (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Susan Van Gaabeek (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - Pamela Veach (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - Gary Volbracht (Box 90, Folder 8)
  - Joyce VonHolt (Box 90, Folder 9)
  - Frank Waldhaus (Box 90, Folder 10)
  - Betty Walten (Box 90, Folder 11)
  - Barbara Warning (Box 90, Folder 12)
  - Paula Warrick (Box 90, Folder 13)
  - Richard Wentura (Box 90, Folder 14)
  - Peter Wheeler (Box 90, Folder 15)
  - Gerald Whitaker (Box 90, Folder 16)
  - Whitaker, John Marshall (Box 90, Folder 17)
  - Tayal, Shanti (Box 90, Folder 18)
  - Li Johnson Interviews (Box 90, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous A-F (Box 90, Folder 20)
  - Home Study Interviews (Administration) (Box 90, Folder 21)
  - G-Miscellaneous (Box 90, Folder 22)
  - H-Miscellaneous (Box 90, Folder 23)
  - I-O-Miscellaneous (Box 90, Folder 24)
  - P-V-Miscellaneous (Box 90, Folder 25)
  - X Group Roster (Box 90, Folder 26)
  - Junker Interviews (Box 90, Folder 27)
  - Charles V. Matthews (Box 90, Folder 28)
  - James Mitchell (Box 90, Folder 29)
  - Reprints (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - Publication by Staff (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - Comments on Growing up in River City (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - Publication: "A Community Youth Development Plan" (The School Review, 1951) (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - Rosters-QYDC-X-Group, 1953-54 (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - Y-Group Rosters (Box 91, Folder 6)
  - Budgets (Box 91, Folder 7)
  - X-Group (1942) Lists of Selected Children, Strictly Confidential (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - Y-Group Roster (Box 91, Folder 9)
  - Improving the Education of the Disadvantaged in an Elementary Setting (Box 91, Folder 10)
  - Havighurst et al: Growing Up in River City (Box 91, Folder 11)
  - Quincy Youth Development Commission Casebook, 1951 (Box 91, Folder 12)
  - Research Methods: Background Material (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - QYDC Papers, vol. 1: Monographs (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - QYDC Papers, vol. 2: Teacher Handbooks (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - QYDC Papers, vol. 3: Articles (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - QYDC Papers, vol. 4: Dropout Study (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - QYDC Papers, vol. 6: Assorted Papers (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - Pierce, Bright High and Low Achievers: A Comparison (Box 93, Folder 3)